So, I want to show this is a tweet that
you made recently. This is regarding the
Iran war. Every American casualty, every
plane lost, every death, every child
left without a parent, every dollar
spent, every cost of living increase,
every hardship that this war creates.
All of it is on Trump and his inability
to be a man and to just tell Netanyahu
to [__]
off. So, here is John Kiriakou, former
CIA officer,
kind of flushing out this point here of
just how controlled by Israel Trump is,
making the point that Trump is not the
first president that Israel insisted
bomb Iran on their behalf, but he's the
first one who couldn't tell him no.
In all the years that I was in the CIA,
no matter who the Israeli prime minister
was, every single time an Israeli prime
minister came to Washington, no matter
who the president happened to be, the
Israelis would say, "Please help us bomb
Iran. Please help us bomb Iran. Please
help us bomb Iran." And the presidents
always said, "No." Until this one. I
think that President
President Trump was duped by Benjamin
Netanyahu, and now we're in a war that
that is not ours from the beginning and
that we cannot win. And this is another
thing, too. My own experience in the CIA
and and at some of the highest levels of
government, I was the executive
assistant to the CIA's deputy director
throughout the
the Iraq war. There's never an exit
strategy. It's easy to attack a country.
It's easy to overthrow a government, but
then what do you do? That's the hard
part.
And he makes essentially the same point
here, goes into a little more detail.
This is a clip of Kiriakou on the Megan
Kelly show.
years that I was in the CIA,
literally every time an Israeli prime
minister came to the United States, and
they come all the time,
regardless of who happened to be the
president, whether it was Ronald Reagan
all the way in into Donald Trump's first
term, every single Israeli prime
minister would come and say, "Please
bomb Iran. Please bomb Iran. Please bomb
Iran." And every president would say,
"No, we're not going to bomb Iran."
Until this president. And the Israelis
from 1986,
the Israelis have have been saying that
the Iranians were 6 months away from a
nuclear bomb. Just simply not true. The
the CIA in the last 20 years has written
two national intelligence estimates.
Now, this is a sense of the entire
intelligence community concluding both
times that the Iranians did not have a
nuclear weapons program.
So, it seems like what Kiriakou is
saying there is that Trump was the only
guy who Israel could convince to do
this, convince in air quotes, of course.
Since they have their own ways of
convincing people to do things.
So, this seems strong evidence to me
that not only is Israel calling the
shots, but that they needed someone as
under their thumb as Donald Trump to get
the war they always wanted. Now, there's
another school of thought which is being
sort of debated on X right now. I'm sure
you've run into this debate in your own
circles, which says that no, Israel is
our puppet and they're following our
lead because really it's Washington who
wants this war. And that to blame Israel
is somehow to let Washington off the
hook. So, where do you land in that
debate?
Well, I'll give a straight answer and
then I'll give a nuanced answer.
Straight answer is this is Israel's war.
Like, crystal clear. Um nuanced take is
that the people that argue that there
are people um
they're not entirely wrong. I mean,
there are elements that are in the
military industrial complex, etc., that
that donate to politicians, that have
lobbying
uh you know, activities that are trying
to get politicians to fight these wars,
but they are fighting these wars for
Israel.
Like, [laughter]
let's be clear about that. Uh so,
I mean, you don't have to just take
Kiriakou's word for it. Uh
if you don't believe Joe Kent, then you
can dig into the actual history of the
Iraq war to find out how that all played
out. Um
I mean, the clean break memo is huge,
you know, PNAC, Project for a New
American Century, the all the guys that
got into George Bush Jr.'s White House.
It's crystal clear that this was a
you know, Jewish-American
Israeli-Jewish movement to essentially
use our military to destroy all of
Israel's enemies and to enable them to
take
Palestine. Like
>> [laughter]
>> And beyond. Well, sure. Sure. It's well,
it's expanded now because it's been so
successful. Um but I'm not sure that
they actually expected that they could
go further than just taking Palestine,
but they are now expanding into like
full greater Israel project. So, I mean,
it to me it's like it's just laughable
that we even have to debate this. Um
it's very frustrating, and I feel bad
for Dave Smith cuz that's now his career
is he has to go around talking to
water-carrying hacks like Coleman Hughes
to explain, you know, just because the
West Clark seven isn't an open and shut
case as to whether or not that actually
was you know, provable that he saw that
that that was the plan. We went and we
took over those seven countries. Did he
guess that?
Right. [laughter] Right.
>> Come on, man.
Um and then you add in all of the other
things that we just talked about. And
there's so much more. You can get to
Mearsheimer and it's like there's just
ample evidence to be completely
convinced that Israel is dictating our
foreign policy, particularly when it
comes to to the Middle East, but I think
it also has it has its tendrils, no
anti-Semitic
intention,
>> [laughter]
>> into
into
>> hooks and its its horns into into other
things, yeah.
>> That's better. That's better. [laughter]
And I got to be safe. Um
But the Venezuela war, man, they were
they were also supportive of the Gazans.
So, it's like
I think that they have sway that is
really incalculable. I mean, it's it's
astronomical. I mean, they were
deporting college students for speaking
out against Israel. It's like
I just don't know how
Like and I and I'm not fond of many of
the college progressives. I mean, many
of them would like to see me
>> [laughter]
>> tortured, but I still want them to be
able to speak freely.
Um so, I don't know. It's just all it's
all madness. And and then the obvious
like op that we've witnessed in terms of
taking over the influencer class, you
know, the skin suiting of MAGA and skin
suiting of America First is so so
egregious and obvious to me because I
was actually like deep in the weeds when
I was watching all these people that
were pushing the Kamala Harris as the
president of war, you know, or the
candidate of war, and
Trump is the president of peace, and gas
is going to be cheaper, and no more
wars, and then they all flip on a dime,
and and I know for a fact that these
people are getting paid. Like, I know
it. So,
it's an op, and there's like major money
going into it. And then you do the
research, you find out about Project
Esther, and you realize that there's
tens of millions, if not hundreds of
millions, if not God knows how much
money that's going into propaganda
campaigns that are specifically targeted
towards the American people on benefit
on on the behalf and benefit of Israel,
a foreign government. Then you look at
the FARA filings, and you recognize that
like basically [laughter]
the only country that's able to to do
this
without running against the law seems to
be Israel. It's just the the double
standards over and over again. It just
keeps coming up and coming up and coming
up. And then
once you understand the origins of the
war of the wars for my entire adult
life, and if you don't know all the
history, then you can go read Scott
Horton's great book, he'll lay it all
out for you. But I mean, it's just like
this is just this is not a debate. This
Israel is running the show. I realize it
doesn't make sense because we're the big
and powerful and rich country, but it
doesn't change the fact that the actions
don't make sense unless you actually
attribute them to being driven on behalf
of Israel.
Yeah. No, I think you're right. And you
the the clean break memo highlights Iraq
and Syria. Syria was, of course,
necessary to knock off before the Iran
war because Syria was the most
formidable country in the Middle East
like militarily,
you know, who could have fought this war
off on the Iranian side. And so, you
know, it was or at least be a stalwart
against that kind of
expansion. So, it it really
when you put everything together, you
know, RFK called Israel our aircraft
carrier.
And it may be true that there is a
strategic influence strategic benefit
for the West to have a sort of satellite
state over there. Um but at a certain
point I think, you know, to to deny that
Israel is in the driver's seat,
especially when it comes to this war.
Because this war is so suicidally
insane. It's not even winnable. Like,
there's not even really an imperial
interest for us to fight it. We lost it.
We lost it in a in a week. We've clearly
lost it already. That's why Trump is
melting down now. So, yeah, I mean, I
think that that debate is just become
kind of a really frustrating one. I
think that's happening kind of on the
left and on the right, this question of
a chicken or the egg. Well, whose war is
it? You know, they clearly benefit
Israel. Go ahead. Well, and I didn't
even talk about the fact that Marco
Rubio said it was for Israel. And Donald
Trump said it was for Israel. And Pete
Hegseth said it was for Israel. It was
like, "What are we doing here?" Like,
it's obviously for Israel. Yes, it was
for Israel's defense. Um Well,
defense.
>> [laughter]
>> Defense after they aggress, but you know
what I'm saying. Um so, yeah, it's it's
totally laughable, and and I think that
that's that's been kind of the unifying
talking point that has allowed for
probably you and I to cross over or me
and Ana Kasparian or
think or, you know, Scott and Dave and
all of us is like we just I think that's
really the tie that binds is that we're
all recognizing that we don't have
sovereignty. And I do want to correct
one thing that you said, it's not your
fault, but you know, I think it was you
said RFK said it that there are aircraft
carrier that's been a very common
talking point forever. We don't have
bases there.
Like like so if there are aircraft
carrier, you think we'd be able to do
whatever we want that we'd be stationing
our sorties out of there. And it's like
that's not how this goes. Like we have
bases in Bahrain and Kuwait and Saudi
and all these other nations, but we
don't have like This is that's the other
reason you know that that they're not
our
pitbull or that we are their pitbull is
like we fight their wars, they don't do
[__] for us. We fund their wars, we arm
their wars, we die in their wars, they
don't do any of that for us. None of it.
And yet people still argue that they are
pitbull. It's like [__] they are
pitbull. We are fighting people that are
our enemies only because we've been
fighting people that are their enemies
forever and now they hate us. That's as
simple as it can get. And it just drives
me absolutely insane that we can't just
all recognize it for what it is.
And I think it just all boils down to
the the curse of both Christian Zionism
and the
the
really successful campaign to convince
everybody
that
any criticism of the nation-state of
Israel is somehow bigoted hatred of a
ethnic minority. Whatever.
>> And I that that whole
scam has to die. It has to.
So. Well, I mean, I think it is. I mean,
it's not working anymore. I mean, fewer
and fewer people are even bothering to
defend themselves against accusations of
anti-Semitism. True. It's like I don't
even want to hear it. Like don't even
bother
>> Well, in our world in our world, you're
right. But in day-to-day life, I think
it's it's a lot harder for people. Like
at the water cooler, you're probably not
talking about you know Right. Sure.
Yeah. And now I think that's that's
definitely true.
Please clap.
Woo!
>> [applause]